
/* Reasoning Quiz Questions
 * creating an array and passing the number, questions, options, and answers
 */

let questions = [

/* Q1 */
    {
      numb: 1,
      question: "What number should come next <br> <strong style= 'color: violet'>7, 10, 8, 11, 9, 12, ...? </strong>",
      options: [
                "A) 7",
                "B) 10",
                "C) 12",
                "D) 13"
               ],
      answer: "B) 10"
    },

/* Q2 */
    {
      numb: 2,
      question: "What number should come next <br> <strong style='color: violet'>22, 21, 23, 22, 24, 23, ...? <strong>",
      options: [
                "A) 22",
                "B) 24",
                "C) 25",
                "D) 26"
               ],
      answer: "C) 25"
    },

/* Q3 */    
    {
      numb: 3,
      question: "Fill the blank in series <br> SCD, TEF, UGH, ____, WKL",
      options: [
                "A) CMN",
                "B) UJI",
                "C) VIJ",
                "D) IJT"
               ],
      answer: "C) VIJ"
    },
  

/* Q4 */
  {
      numb: 4,
      question: "One morning Udai and Vishal were talking to each other face to face at a crossing. If Vishal's shadow was exactly to the left of Udai, which direction was Udai facing?",
      options: [
                "A) East",
                "B) West",
                "C) North",
                "D) South"
               ],
      answer: "C) North"
    },
/*Copy till here*/
  
/* Q5 */     
  {
      numb: 5,
      question: "If South-East becomes North, North-East becomes West and so on. What will West become?",
      options: [
                "A) North-East",
                "B) North-West",
                "C) South-East",
                "D) South-West"
               ],
      answer: "C) South-East"
    },
/*Copy till here*/

/* Q6 */     
  {
      numb: 6,
      question: "A, P, R, X, S and Z are sitting in a row. S and Z are in the centre. A and P are at the ends. R is sitting to the left of A. Who is to the right of P?",
      options: [
                "A) A",
                "B) X",
                "C) S",
                "D) Z"
               ],
      answer: "B) X"
    },
/*Copy till here*/

/* Q7 */     
  {
      numb: 7,
      question: "Pointing to a photograph of a boy Suresh said, 'He is the son of the only son of my mother.' How is Suresh related to that boy?",
      options: [
                "A) Brother",
                "B) Uncle",
                "C) Cousin",
                "D) Father"
               ],
      answer: "D) Father"
    },
/*Copy till here*/

/* Q8 */ 
  {
      numb: 8,
      question: "Introducing a boy, a girl said, 'He is the son of the daughter of the father of my uncle.' How is the boy related to the girl?",
      options: [
                "A) Brother",
                "B) Nephew",
                "C) Uncle",
                "D) Son-in-law"
               ],
      answer: "A) Brother"
    },
/*Copy till here*/

/* Q9 */ 
  {
      numb: 9,
      question: "Find out the alternative which will replace the question mark. <br> CUP : LIP :: BIRD : ?",
      options: [
                "A) BUSH",
                "B) GRASS",
                "C) FOREST",
                "D) BEAK"
               ],
      answer: "D) BEAK"
    },
/*Copy till here*/


/* Q10 */    
  {
      numb: 10,
      question: "Find out the alternative which will replace the question mark. <br> Flow : River :: Stagnant : ?",
      options: [
                "A) Rain",
                "B) Stream",
                "C) Pool",
                "D) Canal"
               ],
      answer: "C) Pool"
    },
/*Copy till here*/




]; /* Array close*/